A Guide to the Records of Multicultural Academic Opportunities Program (MAOP), 1993-2017
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Records of Multicultural Academic Opportunities Program (MAOP), 1993-2017
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 5/18/1
0.8 Cubic Feet; 2 boxes
This collection comprises the records of the Multicultural Academic Opportunities Program (MAOP), dating 1993 through 2017. This includes printed emails, newspaper articles, publicity, and information about the organization's summer research internship. It mainly contains photographs of students participating in the summer research internship, most from the years 2001 through 2004.
Grayson, Randolph, Dr.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Multicultural Academics Opportunities Program
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transfered to Special Collections in 2019.
Administrative Note
The Multicultural Academic Opportunities Program (MAOP) is a organization that focuses on promoting diversity at Virginia Tech. The program helps undergraduate and graduate students with academic, emotional, social, and financial support and guidance. For undergraduates interested in possible graduate education, MAOP provides summer research opportunities.
Scope and Content
This collection contains a variety of documents about Virginia Tech's Multicultural Academic Opportunities Program (MAOP) from 1993 through 2017. This includes correspondence and printed emails within the MAOP organization, brochures and flyers, newspaper articles, and information about summer research internships and participating students. The bulk of the collection comprises photographs of students involved in the summer research internship. Most of these are of the students researching and presenting their projects, but there are also some photos of the students enjoying other fun activities like going to camp and bowling.
Arrangement
This collection has four series, arranged by type. Files within each series are arranged chronologically.
Series I: Correspondence includes one folder with printed emails within the MAOP organization.
Series II: Publicity has ads for the summer internship program and newspaper articles about MAOP.
Series III: Students has intern and mentor information, a graduate students of distinction booklet, and a student project from the MAOP summer internship.
Series IV: Photos, by far the largest, mostly includes pictures of students involved in the summer internship program.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Diversity in higher education; Photographs; University History; University Archives
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Multicultural Academics Opportunities Program
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence, 2002-2007, undated
  - MAOP Correspondence, 2002, 2005, 2006, 2007, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Publicity, 1999-2015, undated
  - MAOP Publicity, 1999-2000, 2002-2003, 2008-2009, 2015, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MAOP Newspaper Articles, 1999-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series III: Students, 1999-2007
  - MAOP Interns and Mentors, 1999, 2003-2007, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MAOP Graduate Students of Distinction, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A MAOP Project, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1993-2017
  - MAOP Composite Photos (SRI), 1993, 1996-2009, 2014-2017 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MAOP Summer Research Internship, 1993, 1997, 1999, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MAOP Summer Research Internship Photos, 2002-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - MAOP Summer Research Internship, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - MAOP Presentations, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Individuals and Projects, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MAOP Individuals Learning, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - MAOP - Activities, 2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - MAOP Camping/Bowling, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - MAOP Participants, 2001, 2008. undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - MAOP Photographs - SRI and Events, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Individual Student Photos, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)